Guide to the Papers of Harrison Salisbury,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Box Listing (unsorted)
  - Salisbury, H. E. Moscow Trip: Khrushchev Trip - PR, 1959 (Box 207, Folder 3)
  - Salisbury, H. E. Attacks on: by Timur (Tibor) Szamuely -- V. Vasin of Pravda -- 1967 Anniversary: Includes Salisbury of Solzhenytsin, "The First Circle", and Robert Conquest, "The Great Terror", (Book, Reviews ) (Box 207, Folder 4)
  - Salisbury, H. E. Public Relations, 1959-1962 (Box 207, Folder 5)
  - Salisbury, H. E. The 900 Days: Italian 1m Lira Prize Award -- 4 of Salisbury (8x10, b&w), 1970-1973, (Photos, Newspaper ) (Box 207, Folder 6)
  - Photos, Correspondence: Legal reg. 349 E. 84th St. house - re construction next door, damages, repairs, 1967-1970 (Box 207, Folder 7)
  - Kibel Plans: Plans for apt. tower at 84th St. and 1st Ave., adjacent to Salisbury property -- See also folder #7, 1967 (Box 207, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Documents: re purchase of 349 E. 84th St. property, improvements, insurance, including plans, 1965 (Box 207, Folder 9)
  - Trivia: re purchase of 349 E. 84th St. house including financial information, (Correspondence, Notes ) (Box 207, Folder 10)
  - Saltikovka, New York Times: 1956 Dem. Convention, etc., (Photographs) (Box 208, Folder 1)
  - Salisbury Random Prints: Salisbury, Mike, Khrushchev at Exhibition -- some w/descriptions, Soviet Union, 1959, (Photographs) (Box 208, Folder 2)
  - Salisbury, H. E. World War II: Wartime Passport -- 1954-55 Who's Who bio of Salisbury, Algiers Poltave etc., (Photographs) (Box 208, Folder 3)
  - Evansville-Mazo 16, Longfellow-Minnehaha 14, T Falls,Wealthwood, (Photos, Labelled Envelopes ) (Box 208, Folder 4)
  - Salisbury, H. E. Photos: Of Early Years: Boy Scouts, etc. to age 30 (Box 208, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous: Salisbury in Russia, China, Vietnam, etc. -- This combines the contents of 2 unlabelled envelopes, (Book, Photos, Jacket, Publicity Material ) (Box 208, Folder 6)
  - Special Pictures: Salisbury as Boy Scout, Tbilisi 1980, Bobby Kennedy and other misc, (Photos ) (Box 208, Folder 7)
  - Family and Other, (Photos ) (Box 208, Folder 8)
  - Early Mike Salisbury: Mostly one of a kind, (Photos ) (Box 208, Folder 9)
  - Nixon, Richard USSR Trips: Negatives and sketchy captions. See Also: Box C18-1 (no folders), 1959, (Photo ) (Box 209, Folder 10)
  - Salisbury, H. E. Marriage, 1964 (Box 209, Folder 11)
  - New York Times Souvenir EDNs: Candlelight issues of New York Times: new form of international edition, published in Paris, June 1961 re blackout, Paris, 1960-1961 (Box 209, Folder 12)
  - Larson, A. B. Correspondence: To/from Arnold Byron "Wolf" Larson and wife Mary, 1965-1981 (Box 209, Folder 13)
  - Salisbury, M. J. Correspondence: Re trust fund for Salisbury sons with reswick and Handler, 1950-1968 (Box 209, Folder 14)
  - New Emperors -- Mostly labelled on back -- Also some pix for The Long March (Box 209, Folder 15)
  - Photographs: Of China, Russia, Vietnam, Tienanmen (Box 209, Folder 16)
  - Soong Ching Ling Materials: Mostly memorial, 1981-1985 (Box 214, Folder 24)
  - Photographs: Pictures of fire in N. China (near Mongolia), including oversize, 1987 (Box 210, Folder 17)
  - Tienanmen, 1989, (Photographs) (Box 210, Folder 18)
  - Photographs: Blowup of Janet -- Negatives of childhood of Salisbury and sister Janet -- Other misc. -- Some negatives and slides (Box 210, Folder 19)
  - War Between Russia and China: Sovfoto related to same subject, (Photographs) (Box 210, Folder 20)
  - Wartime Pictures of Salisbury, Sept 1978, ( Photographs) (Box 210, Folder 21)
  - Career Pictures: Including re "Journey for Our Times", (Letter, photographs) (Box 210, Folder 22)
  - Photographs: b&w, 8X10. Some duplicates and negatives, Hanoi, 1966-1967 (Box 210, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous of Chinese leaders: Few pieces unrelated, (Photographs, Correspondence, Travel Documents ) (Box 210, Folder 24)
  - Alley, Rewi Incl. material about Alley (d. 12-30-87) -- Material re Chinese industrial cooperatives, "Gung Ho Newsletter", 1967-1992 (Box 211, Folder 1)
  - Chen Family: Jack, Percy, etc.: Herbert Marshall, Ediors Clubb -- Material re Chinese opera in America, 1970-1988, (Correspondence, Publications ) (Box 211, Folder 2)
  - Chen: Jack, Percy, Yua Soong Ching Ling (Mme. Sun Yat-sen) Foundation, 1977-1991 (Box 211, Folder 3)
  - Dimond, E. Grey Edgar Snow Symposium and Edgar Snow Memorial Fund: Incl. bust of E. Snow in Beijing, 1985-1993, (Interview, Photo, etc.) (Box 211, Folder 4)
  - Epstein, Israel Magazine, Correspondence: Bound proposal for documentary film, 1983 --, China Reconstructs, 12/84 -- Salisbury/Soong Ching Ling (Mme. Sun Yat-Sen), ca. 1971-75, 1983-1992 (Box 211, Folder 5)
  - Rittenberg, Sydney Copy of Rittenberg in Peking #16, Apr. 1967, 1980 (Box 211, Folder 6)
  - Graham, Margaret Correspondence, 1985-91 (Box 211, Folder 7)
  - Han Suyin (Elizabeth), 1967-1985 (Box 212, Folder 8)
  - Hanxu Biographical: Chinese ambassador to US, ca. 1980, (Notes ) (Box 212, Folder 9)
  - Hatem, George (Ma Haide) Travel to the West By Edgar Snow and Ma Haide - 92 pp., 1979-1991 (Box 212, Folder 10)
  - Huang Hua China Daily, 1985, 1976-1987 (Box 212, Folder 11)
  - Li Zhengjun Correspondence, 1980-1987 (Box 212, Folder 12)
  - Liu Binyan, 1983-1988 (Box 212, Folder 13)
  - Snow, Edgar Symposium Pre-symposium, program, schedule, promotions, 1985 (Box 212, Folder 14)
  - Snow, Edgar Snow Memorial Fund: Includes Salisbury MS on China reporting -- Snow MS of w/ Mao -- Salisbury/E Snow, 1961-1971, (Interview, Correspondence ) (Box 212, Folder 15)
  - Snow, Helen Nomination of H. Snow for Nobel Peace Prize, 1981 -- Incl. more material re Edgar Snow Memorial Fund, 1979-1981 (Box 212, Folder 16)
  - Snow, Helen Writings by Helen Snow Miscellaneous material re various Old China Hands -- Material re Committee for Industrial Cooperatives -- English and Chinese, 1983-1992 (Box 213, Folder 17)
  - Snow, H Other H Snow writings -- The Long March: More material on industrial cooperatives, 1972-1985, (Interview, Correspondence, Notes, Research ) (Box 213, Folder 18)
  - Snow, Helen Gung Ho Papers: re Chinese industrial cooperatives -- Bound (Box 213, Folder 19)
  - Snow, Helen Other H Snow Writings: MS "On the Left-Wing Painters and Modern Art in China" by Nym Wales -- Bibliography of Nym Wales, 1980, (Correspondence, Notes ) (Box 213, Folder 20)
  - 3rd Edgar Snow Symposium, 1988 Incl. Chinese publication of Red Star Over China on 50th anniversary of original publication -- Edgar Snow Memorial Fund, 1987-1991 (Box 214, Folder 21)
  - Soong Ching Ling (Mme Sun Yat-sen) & Jeanette Sui (Soong's goddaughter) Salisbury w/ Soong MS of (Salisbury and others) -- Some material re Edgar Snow -- 1971 Chinese calendar, 1971-1987 (Box 214, Folder 22)
  - Soong Ching Ling Letters: Salisbury to/from Soong, 1971-1981 (Box 214, Folder 23)
  - Stanley, Margaret Correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 214, Folder 25)
  - Stanford Scandalre anthropologist's study of forced late-term abortions in Chinese village -- Material re Fulbright application of Old Calendar Greek Orthaodox priest (in US) to study church in Greece (Box 214, Folder 26)
  - Strong, Anna Louise (Box 214, Folder 27)
  - Salisbury - China: -- Chinese government, US government, New York Times re permission to enter China -- Draft of Salisbury re Sino-Soviet denials of split, 1966-1983 (Box 215, Folder 28)
  - China: Chinese, 1971-1974, (Correspondence ) (Box 215, Folder 29)
  - China Trip, 1977, (Notes ) (Box 215, Folder 30)
  - China Trip, 1980, (Correspondence, Notes ) (Box 215, Folder 31)
  - China Trip: May duplicate material in #31, 1980, (Transcript, Notes ) (Box 215, Folder 32)
  - China Writers: Lists of Chinese and US delegations -- b&w and unlabelled photos, 1986, (Photos, Correspondence, Notes ) (Box 215, Folder 33)
  - China, 1988-1989, (Correspondence, Notes ) (Box 215, Folder 34)
  - China: -- Incl. re Chinese Writers Association and International Writing Program, 1978-1986 (Box 215, Folder 35)
  - No. 1 China File - My: Including with Jack Chen -- See folders 2 and 3, box 30-1, 1978-1983, (Interview, Correspondence, Notes ) (Box 215, Folder 36)
  - China, 1977-1986 (Box 215, Folder 37)
  - China: Miscellaneous: Incl. Salisbury to Chou -Enlai, 1961, 1969 -- Monograph: Central Asia Collectanea, one of a series, 1959, 1959-1980, (Letters, Interview, Notes ) (Box 215, Folder 38)
  - Visit to China: Including re 3rd Edgar Snow symposium -- re Chinese leadership, Spring 1988, (Correspondence, Notes, Business Cards ) (Box 215, Folder 39)
  - Tannenbaum, Jerry / Yuan Chi Interview, Notes: Handwritten and typed, 1977-1981 (Box 216, Folder 40)
  - Yao Wei, 1978-1986 (Box 216, Folder 41)
  - Zhang Jie, Tang Di Situation in China -- Some in Chinese, apparently also translated, 1983-1992 (Box 216, Folder 42)
  - Zhao Ziyang China: -- 13th Congress of CP of China Advance Along the Road of Socialism with Chinese Characteristics (10/25/87) -- Draft Revision of some of the Constitution of the Communist Party of China, 1987 (Box 216, Folder 43)
  - China, 1970-1979 (Box 216, Folder 44)
  - China: -- 100 Years of Revolution w/Tannenbaum, etc., photocopied from Foreign Affairs, 1949 (Box 216, Folder 45)
  - China: -- Top Policy The Dynamics of Factions and Consensus in Chinese Politics, 1980-1981 (Box 216, Folder 46)
  - [China?]: Copies of missionary from China, 1927, 1931 -- Small (in Chinese w/ English title), "Captivity and Answered Prayer in China," apparently by Bosshardt, translated into Chinese by Zhong Guoqi -- Unidentified, similar to painting on jacket, 1984-1992, (Letters, Book, etc.) (Box 217, Folder 1)
  - Neils, Patricia Symposium on The Impact of American Missionaries on US Attitudes and Policies Toward China: Incl. "The Triumph of John and Betty Stam", by Mrs. Howard Taylor, China Inland Mission, 1936, San Diego, 1987, (Book, Correspondence ) (Box 217, Folder 2)
  - China: -- Missionaries and Others Incl. The Craighills of China, Marian G. Craighill, 1972, 1985-1989 (Box 217, Folder 3)
  - The Long March: Names and Places: Spiral with listings in alphabetical order -- 2 columns on each page -- "people" and "places", (Notebook ) (Box 217, Folder 4)
  - The Long March: re project, including requests, 1983-1984, (Interview, Correspondence, etc.) (Box 217, Folder 5)
  - The Long March: Some possible MS pages. Mostly handwritten, some typed, (Photocopies, Notes, Maps ) (Box 218, Folder 6)
  - Working Papers: Mostly Gen. Qin, Peggy Dennis, Ross Terrill -- Published biographical material on Chinese leaders, 1983-1988, (Photocopies, Interview, etc.) (Box 218, Folder 7)
  - Re. Publication of The Long March: Some published material in Chinese (originals and copies), 1984-1985, (Photo, Correspondence, etc.) (Box 218, Folder 8)
  - The Long March 1: Some pp. of Chinese poetry, Mar 5-Apr 3, 1984, (Interviews, Notes, Typed Trancripts ) (Box 218, Folder 9)
  - The Long March 2, Apr 3-Jun 12, 1984, (Interviews, Notes, Typed Trancripts ) (Box 218, Folder 10)
  - The Long March 3: Several pp. of personal thoughts, Jun 12-16, 1984, (Interviews, Notes, Typed Trancripts ) (Box 219, Folder 11)
  - The Long March 4, Oct 24-Nov 3, 1984, (Interviews ) (Box 219, Folder 12)
  - Service, John S. Letter, Books, Correspondence: J Service, Caroline Service, Ross Terrill -- Poetry by Caroline Service (under pseudonym), and Virginia (Service) McCormick, 1984-1992 (Box 219, Folder 13)
  - J Service The Long March, Sep 1, 1983-Jan 16, 1985, (Photocopies, Correspondence, etc.) (Box 219, Folder 14)
  - The Long March: w/ Zhang Yuan Yuan, Chang Hai-Lang, 1984-1988, (Interview, Correspondence, Notes ) (Box 219, Folder 15)
  - The Long March: To Zhang Yuan Yuan, 1984-1989, (Correspondence ) (Box 219, Folder 16)
  - The Long March: w/ Hanson, Haldore, 1983-1987, (Interview, Correspondence, Notes ) (Box 219, Folder 17)
  - Mei Shan Interview, Transcript, Notes, 1984-1985 (Box 220, Folder 18)
  - Wang Bingnan, Zhang Wenjin, Ling Quin Friendship Assoc.: MS of w/ preface and partial duplicate copy, 1984-1988, (Memoir, Interview, Correspondence, Notes ) (Box 220, Folder 19)
  - Yang Shangkun & Mme. Li Bochao Newspaper, Correspondence, Asiaweek Page, 1984-1987 (Box 220, Folder 20)
  - Ed Snow, Han Suyin, Chen, Huang, Chen The Long March Print Sources, (Photocopies, Books, etc. ) (Box 220, Folder 21)
  - Service, Caroline The Long March: -- Material from Long March (1935) and Cultural Revolution (1970): w/ cover, 1984, (Letter, Photocopies ) (Box 220, Folder 22)
  - Yang Bingzhang Handwritten translation of pages from Chinese, 1983-1986 (Box 220, Folder 23)
  - He Zizhen The Long March Print: Geographic, in English, Chinese and French, (Photocopies, Newspapers, Magazines ) (Box 220, Folder 24)
  - Huang Tsing, 1984 (Box 221, Folder 25)
  - Li Xiannian & Li Xiaolin (daughter) Interview, Newspapers, Correspondence, Notes, Press Release: US and Chinese, 1984-1986 (Box 221, Folder 26)
  - Li Xiannian White House Memorabilia: re White House reception and dinner, Jul 23, 1985, (Invitations, Placecards, etc.) (Box 221, Folder 27)
  - The Long March miscellaneous (Box 221, Folder 28)
  - Notebooks: Spiral, 7-3/4 "x 5" (Box 221)
  - Notebook: Chi Shui River, Maotai, Yunnan, Dali, Lijiang, Shiqui, Kunming, Du Kau, Jianping Du, Xichang, Cheng Diu, Luding (Box 221, Folder 4)
  - China's Long March, Chataqua, 1986 (Box 221, Folder 29)
  - The Long March: Chinese translation of, with translation of introduction, (Letter ) (Box 222, Folder 29)
  - The Long March: Duplicates -- Box 31-2, folders 9, 10 and 31-3, folders 11, 12, and possibly others, (Photocopies, Transcripts, Notes ) (Box 222, Folder 30)
  - Notebooks, Transcripts: Folder Series of black ring, containing typed of earlier (19th-century) material (Box 223)
  - Letters: Along with typed transcripts, some originals and a drawing, 1864-1866 (Box 223)
  - In Grandfather's Desk: Large ring binders #1, with black cover: Copies of documents - originals provided to Salisbury by Hazel Hopkins -- "Grandfather" was Chauncey, son of Hiram Salisbury, June 1985, (Documents, Photos ) (Box 224, Folder 2)
  - Salisbury Genealogy: With index tabs to individual names (Box 224, Folder 2)
  - Family Books: Formerly belonging to Chauncey Salisbury (and possibly others) -- Some loose legal sheets with Salisbury, (Books, Notes ) (Box 225)
  - Amasa Salisbury Account: Copies of Amasa Accounts in Salisbury family originals, ca. 1823-1850, (Letters, Book, etc.) (Box 226, Folder 1)
  - Salisbury Family line: Old typed copy and photocopy, 1885 (Box 226, Folder 2)
  - Hiram Salisbury Hiram Salisbury and family of Jessie D. Ross and Susanne Salisbury, 1938-44 (in envelope) and other family, 1924-38 -- See black notebook in 32-2, Chepachet Rhode Island, 1978-1985 (Box 226, Folder 3)
  - Rich G. and Edna Kent, Hazel Hopkins, Milton Thoene, and Thelma Galten Photocopies, Photocopy, etc.: Mostly re Hiram S and family, Chepachet, 1815-1843 (Box 226, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Notes, Research: re Salisbury family in Canandaigua, Canandaigua NY (Box 226, Folder 5)
  - Photocopies, Photos, etc., Buffalo, 1983-1986 (Box 226, Folder 6)
  - Hiram Including Unforgettable Uncle Hiram, by Salisbury -- Salisbury with Readers' Digest (Box 227, Folder 7)
  - Original Hiram: Incl. "From Grandfaather's Desk", Hazel Hopkins (copied) -- See black notebook, Box 32-2, June 1985, (Documents, Letters ) (Box 227, Folder 8)
  - The First Buffalo Family: Incl. text w/ and appendices, pp 211 -- "Guide to the Study of United States Imprints" -- Broadsides Printed at Canandaigua, NY, 1799-1850, 1956, (Photocopy, Books, etc.) (Box 227, Folder 9)
  - Hezekiah A. Salisbury Deeds: Photocopies and originals, 1820-1844 (Box 227, Folder 10)
  - Van Norman Ancestors of Sarah Spear Salisbury: From county records, (Correspondence, Notes ) (Box 227, Folder 11)
  - Printed and sold by SH and HA Salisbury, 1812, (Photocopies, Books ) (Box 227, Folder 12)
  - Salisbury family -- [Salisbury grandfather was from Mazomanie], Mazomanie Wisconsin (Box 227, Folder 13)
  - Salisbury Imprints: re Salisbury Brothers printers, (Books, Pamphlets, Bibliographic Material (Photocopied) ) (Box 227, Folder 14)
  - Bits and Pieces: Genealogy, especially from/to Sue Salisbury (Salisbury' aunt) -- Transcriptions of 19th-century documents, ca. 1930s, (Letters, Correspondence ) (Box 227, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Genealogical Material: Salisbury's with Sue Salisbury, 1940-1985 (Box 228, Folder 16)
  - Genealogical Research: Sue's Basic, on Salisburys and Other Related Families - mostly typed and summaries of historical documents and records, some undated -- Material on individual names, family branches, etc., (Clippings, Transcripts, Newspaper ) (Box 228, Folder 17)
  - Hiram, Hezekiah, Amasa, Guy, Osborn Genealogy, Pension, Obituaries, etc., 1827-1968 (Box 228, Folder 18)
  - Alfred P. Salisbury Miscellaneous Salisbury family: -- Oliver M. Salisbury, The Bitter Root, with accompanying to Salisbury from Alfred P. Salisbury -- Box of "papers found in Grandfather (Chauncey) Salisbury's desk" -- Readers' Digest reprint, "Uncle Hiram" -- Salisbury re family line, 1987 (Box 228, Folder 19)
  - Family books, (Printed Material ) (Box 229)
  - Family Some loose old papers in plastic envelopes and re family history, 19th Century (Box 230)
  - United Frequent Flyer, (Plane-Train Schedules ) (Box 231, Folder 1)
  - China:Tiananmen Diary Outline: Pre-publication and other business -- "Goddess of Democracy", (Photo, Correspondence, Reviews ) (Box 231, Folder 2)
  - Little Brown - Debbie Jacobs: re "The Great Black Dragon Fire", "Beyond the New China Gate" (possibly the same as The New Emperors) and "Tiananmen Diary" --, 1988-1990, (Correspondence, Notes, Reviews, Maps ) (Box 231, Folder 3)
  - The Long March: Film, 1984-1992, (Memos, Correspondence, Notes ) (Box 231, Folder 4)
  - Semyonov, Julian The 900 Days: -- Including in Russian, Italian - some re Sergio Leone proposed film project on Leningrad blockade, 1989 -- Other possible film projects, etc., captioned, 1979-1992 (Box 231, Folder 5)
  - Books, Correspondence, Films: re possible films of Salisbury, 1988-1989 (Box 231, Folder 6)
  - Forest Fire: -- Incl. photcopy of by L. Newton Hayes, "The Chinese Dragon", Shanghai, 1922, 1987 (Box 232, Folder 7)
  - Prof. Robock Forest Fire: -- Assorted by Robock re forest fire smoke and surface cooling, forest fire detection, 1988 (Box 232, Folder 8)
  - Fire: re "The Great Black Dragon Fire" by George Breuer, "Weather Modification: Prospects and Problems", Cambridge Univ Press, 1980, (Book, Review, Correspondence, Reviews ) (Box 232, Folder 9)
  - Forest Fire: -- On Chinese forest fire, subject of Salisbury's The Great Black Dragon Fire and related topics, 1987 (Box 232, Folder 10)
  - The Long March -- Re Chinese leaders and policies, 1987-1988 (Box 232, Folder 11)
  - The Long March: New York Times op-ed 10-1-88: Salisbury on Black Dragon Fire -- Excerpt from Sheehan's "A Bright Shining Lie" -- New Long March and New Emperors, 1988, (Book, Photos, Correspondence, Reviews ) (Box 232, Folder 12)
  - The Long March: Incl. Uncaptioned snapshot, 1986-1989, (Photo, Correspondence, Notes, Concert Program ) (Box 232, Folder 13)
  - The Long March, 1984-1988, (Review, Correspondence, etc.) (Box 233, Folder 14)
  - Tiananmen Diary, Disturber of the Peace and The New Emperors, Unwin Hyman (British publisher), 1988-1992, (Memoirs, Correspondence, Reviews ) (Box 233, Folder 15)
  - Outline: The Long March: -- English translation of Renmin Ribao -- Editorial 2-27-63, "Whence the Difference: - A Reply to Thorez and Other Comrades" -- Copy of Salisbury to Arthur Miller, 8-20-87 -- Captioned on back and letters in Chinese, 1985-1988 (Box 233, Folder 16)
  - Leningrad -- This may relate to a Russian edition of The 900 Days. -- Correspondece including in Russian, 1990-1991 (Box 233, Folder 17)
  - Book, Correspondence, Catalogs, Publishers' Lists, Invoices: Incl. photocopied pages from reference s on China, invoices re purchase of books and re research questions - To and from Salisbury. 1985-1992 (Box 233, Folder 18)
  - The Long March: -- Brokaw with Zhao Aiyang, 9-28-87 -- Chinese embassy press releases, 1986-1987 (Box 234, Folder 19)
  - The Long March Material re 1985 Soviet writers' trip to US, 1986 -- Dartmouth Conference, 1984 and 1986 -- Chinese-American Writers' conferences, and other visits of Chinese writers to US -- MS of Allen Weinstein's "Perjury" (re Alger Hiss) - 32 pp, incomplete and anonymous -- 1984 US-Chinese Writers' Conference, uncaptioned (Box 234, Folder 20)
  - Notebooks, Notes: Spiral, some loose pages (Box 234, Folder 21)
  - K M Simonov Letters, Interview, Correspondence, Notes: Salisbury w/ Simonov and relatives (including in Russian) and other: Some writing by Simonov (in both Russian and English, including translation of a poem) -- RFE Simonov obituary, 1979 -- 2 booklets, in plastic envelopes: The Russian Famine of 1891 and 1892, "Strike, but Hear": Poland, Rusia, and the Polict of the Latter Toward the United States, Baltimore, 1844 -- Simonov was Russian war correspondent and writer, 1978-1981 (Box 235, Folder 1)
  - K M Simonov Interview, Photo, Correspondence, Notes: Salisbury w/ Simonov daughter et al (some re possible English translation of Simonov WWII diary), 1982-1987 (Box 235, Folder 2)
  - K M Simonov Some in Russian, 1989-1991 (Box 235, Folder 3)
  - NHK (Japanese TV network) Materials re documentary: "40 Years of the Chinese revolution: Governing a Billion People - mostly planning: scripts, scenarios, lists of places and people, revisions,, (some post-production), 1988-1991, (Photos, Correspondence, Notes ) (Box 235, Folder 4)
  - Emperors: Travel Expenses I, 1991-1992, (Book, Correspondence, etc.) (Box 235, Folder 5)
  - Dalian: 5" x 7", red, 1987 (Box 237, Folder 6)
  - Emperors: Some in Italian, (Correspondence, Reviews ) (Box 236, Folder 6)
  - Emperors: General, 1991-1992, (Correspondence, Reviews, Jacket Copy ) (Box 236, Folder 7)
  - Emperors: May duplicate #5. Some pages have notes on the back., (Receipts, Expenses, etc.) (Box 236, Folder 8)
  - Emperors: Trip: Li Yueran, Qin Xinghan, Zhu Zhongli, 1991, (Interview, Notes ) (Box 236, Folder 9)
  - Rosetta Stones: Handwritten sheets re Chinese names, including errors or variant forms, (Notes, Maps ) (Box 236, Folder 10)
  - Little Brown: re "New Emperors", including corrections to MS, (Correspondence, Notes, Bibliography ) (Box 236, Folder 11)
  - Small Spiral Notebooks, Notes (Box 237)
  - Interview, Notes: w/ Chinese officials, 1987 (Box 237, Folder 4)
  - Spiral Notebooks: Apparently re China, 1987 (Box 237)
  - Spiral Notebooks: Chinese names (characters and English spelling), etc., 1988 (Box 237)
  - China: Beijing, Apr 25, 1988, (Notes ) (Box 237, Folder 1)
  - China: March, May 8, 1988 (Box 237, Folder 3)
  - China: March, May 19/21, 1988 (Box 237, Folder 4)
  - China: March, May 30, 1988 (Box 237, Folder 5)
  - China: March, 1988 (Box 237, Folder 6)
  - China: Tiananmen Trip: 5" x 7-3/4", tan (no index), 1989 (Box 237, Folder 1)
  - Index: 5" x 7-3/4", tan open to p. 25, Jan 28, 1991 (Box 237, Folder 2)
  - Dalian: 5" x 8", glue on top, no cover, Sept 23, 1987, (Index ) (Box 237, Folder 1)
  - Dalian: 5" x 7-3/4", tan, Sept 4, 1987 (Box 237, Folder 2)
  - Dalian, 1987 (Box 237, Folder 3)
  - Dalian: 7-3/4" x 5", short list of names, Nov 5, 1987 (Box 237, Folder 7)
  - Dalian, Aug 8/17-Sept 4, 1987 (Box 237, Folder 8)
  - G. K. Zhukov: In Russian (Box 238, Folder 12)
  - With the Eyes of a Person of My Generation: by Konstantin Simonov -- in Russian, (pp. 9-121 Photocopy, Book ) (Box 238, Folder 13)
  - Novyi Mir Photocopy: New World, Soviet literary journal, Oct 1966 (Box 238, Folder 14)